[
  {
    "question": "Which of the following correctly declares an array of size 10?",
    "choice1": "int array[10]",
    "choice2": "int array",
    "choice3": "array[10]",
    "choice4": "array array[10]",
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "What will be the output of the following code? int arr[100]; cout << arr[0];",
    "choice1": "0",
    "choice2": "0 or Garbage Value",
    "choice3": "Error",
    "choice4": "Null",
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the index number of the last element of an array with 5 elements?",
    "choice1": "5",
    "choice2": "4",
    "choice3": "3",
    "choice4": "None",
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Deep copy is achived by ______",
    "choice1": "Default Constructor",
    "choice2": "Copy Constructor",
    "choice3": "Friend Constructor",
    "choice4": "None",
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is default access specifier for data members or member functions declared within a class without any specifier, in C++?",
    "choice1": "private",
    "choice2": "protected",
    "choice3": "pubic",
    "choice4": "depends on compiler",
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "Backtracking is best suited for solving problems that involve:",
    "choice1": "Sorting elements",
    "choice2": "Searching in a sorted list",
    "choice3": "Dynamic programming",
    "choice4": "Exploring all possible solutions",
    "answer": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a backtracking algorithm?",
    "choice1": "Knight tour problem",
    "choice2": "M coloring problem",
    "choice3": "Tower of hanoi",
    "choice4": "N queen problem",
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Given an array arr = {12, 13, 35, 78, 56} and key = 78; How many iterations are done until the element is found using Binary search?",
    "choice1": "5",
    "choice2": "1",
    "choice3": "3",
    "choice4": "2",
    "answer": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Whatâ€™s happen if base condition is not defined in recursion?",
    "choice1": "Stack Overflow",
    "choice2": "Stack Underflow",
    "choice3": "None of these",
    "choice4": "Both A and B",
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "Which function is used to get the length of a string object?",
    "choice1": "size",
    "choice2": "max_size",
    "choice3": "length",
    "choice4": "Both size and length",
    "answer": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Which constant member functions does not modify the string?",
    "choice1": "empty()",
    "choice2": "assign",
    "choice3": "append",
    "choice4": "erase",
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the time complexity of binary search algorithm?",
    "choice1": "O(n)",
    "choice2": "O(n^2)",
    "choice3": "O(1)",
    "choice4": "O(log n)",
    "answer": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "The necessary condition for using binary search in an array is :-",
    "choice1": "The array should not be too long",
    "choice2": "The array should of more size",
    "choice3": "The array should be sorted",
    "choice4": "None of these",
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the formula to calculate the address of an ith element of an array?",
    "choice1": "base_address + (data_type_size * index)",
    "choice2": "base_address + (data_type_size * n)",
    "choice3": "(data_type_size * n)",
    "choice4": "base_address + (data_type_size * (index+1))",
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "If integer requires two bytes space, then what will be the size of the following 'C++' array? int arr[3][4];",
    "choice1": "12 bytes",
    "choice2": "7 bytes",
    "choice3": "14 bytes",
    "choice4": "24 bytes",
    "answer": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "The worst case time complexity of linear search is:",
    "choice1": "O(n)",
    "choice2": "O(n logn)",
    "choice3": "O(n*n)",
    "choice4": "O(n log log N)",
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the length of an array when its first index is denoted by i and last index is denoted by j?",
    "choice1": "i + j",
    "choice2": "j - i + 1",
    "choice3": "j - i",
    "choice4": "j - i - 1",
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "The worst case occur in linear search algorithm when -",
    "choice1": "Item is somewhere in the middle of the array",
    "choice2": "Item is not at all in the array",
    "choice3": "Item is present at first index of the array",
    "choice4": "None",
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the limitation of the array?",
    "choice1": "elements can be accesses from anywhere",
    "choice2": "The size of the array is fixed",
    "choice3": "Indexing is started from zero",
    "choice4": "Memory waste if an array's elements are smaller than the size alloted to them",
    "answer": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "The correct syntax for initialization of 1-D array is ___________ .",
    "choice1": "num[4] = {1,2,3,4}",
    "choice2": "num[4] = 0",
    "choice3": "num[4] = {1 2 3 4}",
    "choice4": "num[4] = {1;2;3;4}",
    "answer": 1
  }
]
